Eduardo Cruz Photograph Collection, circa 1881-1891, undated
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Eduardo Cruz Photograph Collection, circa 1881-1891,
MS 247
Cruz, Eduardo, 1860-1939
Studio portraits, mostly cartes-de-visite and cabinet cards, of Eduardo Cruz and other young men and women, probably his friends and classmates. Most are identified by name and were taken by professional photographers in the Laredo, Texas area, ca. 1881-1891.
.25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
A dry goods merchant, Eduardo Cruz was born in 1860 in Nuevo Leon, Mexico and immigrated to Laredo, Texas in 1881. He was married to Margarata Vidaurri, owned a dry goods store, and died in Laredo in 1939.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series
Series I: Photographs, ca. 1881-1891, undated
Scope and Content Note
Studio portraits, chiefly cartes-de-visite and cabinet cards, of Eduardo Cruz and friends, in the Laredo, Texas area, ca.1881-1891. The photographs are inscribed, in Spanish, with greetings to Eduardo from the subject. Surnames include Garza, Garcia, Joseph, Seguin, Schrader, Perez, Olvera, Quintana, Chapa, Pena, Salinas, Trevino, Quiroz, and Zaragoza. Photographers from Laredo are Tomas K. Hamilton, J. Villareal, and Stephenson. Other photographers are Louis de Planque (Corpus Christi), M. Rodriguez Perez (Eagle Pass), and Jose R. Mendez (Matamoros, Mexico).
Access Terms
Cruz, Eduardo--Portraits
Hamilton, Tomas K., Photographer
Planque, Louis de, Photographer
Mexican-Americans--Texas--Laredo--19th century--Portraits
Portrait photography--Texas
Laredo (Tex.)--Social life and customs--Pictorial works
Container List
- Series I: Photographs, circa 1881-1891, undated
  This series is arranged topically.
  - Portraits--Eduardo Cruz, cartes-de-visite, 1883-1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Portraits--Eduardo Cruz, cabinet cards, 1886, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Group portraits with Eduardo Cruz, ca. 1880s, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Portraits--Women, 1885-1886, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Portraits--Men, Identified, A-L, 1882-1883, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Portraits--Men, Identified, M-R, 1881-1891, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Portraits--Men, Identified, S-Z, 1881-1887, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Group portraits--Men, 1882-1883 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Portraits--Men, unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)